TIMOTHY OKOOBOH

7, Ezeagu Street, Apapa, Lagos, Nigeria. okoobohtimothy@gmail.com | +2348176581327

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-okooboh-193980165/

Github: https://github.com/timothyokooboh/
Portfolio: https://timothyokooboh.github.io/portfolio/#/

Professional Summary

I am a frontend software developer with a keen interest in web app optimization and Vue.js development. Therefore, I specialize in the research and creation of performant, reusable, scalable and accessible UI components, while adhering to best practices.

Skills

Front-end languages: HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Javascript, Typescript.

Front-end framework: Vue JS (Vue router, Vuex, Vuetify), Nuxt.JS and Chart.js.

CSS Preprocessor: SASS (SCSS)

Server-side technologies: Express.js, Node.JS, Laravel.

Server-side database: Mysql, Mongo DB.

Version control: Git

Tests: Unit tests with Jest.

Soft skills

- Effective communication
- Problem-solving
- Critical thinking
- Fast learner

Experience

Frontend developer

(August 2020 - Present)

Flux Technology Africa

- Translates UI mockups into responsive, performant and cross-browser compatible web applications.
- Validates user inputs before sending requests to the backend.
- Efficiently consumes Restful APIs on the frontend.
- Assists backend developers in debugging and troubleshooting.

Google Africa Developer Scholarship (ALC 4.0) (May 2019 - November 2019) Mobile Web Specialist

- Built progressive web apps using front-end technologies such as Javascript (ES6), service workers, CSS, HTML and Bootstrap
- Transformed UI mockups into responsive web pages with CSS Grid and Flexbox.
- Built web applications with native web APIs and API clients such as Axios.

Projects

1. **Project name**: 950meals

Project URL: https://950meals.com/

Project description:

950meals is a food delivery service. Users pre-order breakfast and lunch meals which are then prepared by chefs and get delivered by a logistics company.

Technologies used: Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js.

2. **Project name**: Buy-Hub

Project URL: https://buyhub.herokuapp.com/?#/

Project description:

An E-commerce progressive web application. Made by using Express.js and Node.js to build RESTFUL APIs and communicate with the APIs from the frontend with Vue.js.

Technologies used: Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, Axios.

3. **Project name**: Inspirations

Project URL: https://findinspirations.info/

Project description:

A progressive web app where users can create, share and find inspirational stories.

Technologies used: Vue.js, Laravel, Laravel scout.

4. **Project name**: Covid-19 dashboard

Project URL: https://timothyokooboh.github.io/#/

Project description:

Utilizes open-source data from the WHO to display coronavirus statistics for different countries.

Technologies used: Vue.js, Vue router, Chart.js, Axios.

5. **Project name:** Dictionary

Project URL: https://timothyokooboh.github.io/dictionary/#/

Project description: Utilizes the Owlbot-js NPM package to display the meaning and

pronunciation of English words.

Technologies used: Vue.js, Vue router, Owlbot-js NPM package, Axios, Speech synthesis API.

Education

Pharmacy

The University of Benin, Nigeria.

2011 - 2017